A Finding Aid to the John Henry Bradley Storrs Papers, 1790-2007, bulk 1900-1956, in the Archives of American Art AAA.storjohn
Archives of American Art
- Artwork, 1895-1935; Series 8; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 18, 20, OV 23
  Artwork by John Storrs and others. There is a portfolio of pencil drawings and watercolors of people, animals, and plants, as well as portraits of historical figures created by Storrs as a youth. There are a few loose drawings and sketches including two self-portrait sketches. A sketchbook contains pencil drawings of people and scenes from nature. There are 31 lithographs primarily of female figures, and three drawings for proposed murals, including two designs for the Fair Store, Chicago. Artwork in this series by others includes original hand-painted illuminated manuscript pages and a small block print by an unidentified artist.
  - Portfolio of Early Artwork, 1895-1900; (4 folders) (Box 18, Folder 6-9)
  - Loose Drawings and Sketches, circa early-1900s; (See also OV 23) (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Sketchbook, circa early-1900s (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Lithographs, 1932; (Oversized items housed in Box 20) (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Drawings for Murals, circa 1935; (Oversized items housed in OV 23) (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Illustrated Rhyme, circa early-1900s (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Metal Spike Decorated with Two Figures, circa early-1900s (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Illuminated Manuscript Pages, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified Block Print, circa mid-1900s (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Oversize Lithographs, 1932 (Box 20)
    (Scanned with Box 18, F12)
  - Oversize Loose Drawings and Sketches, circa early-1900s (Box OV 23)
    (Scanned with Box 18, F10)
  - Oversize Drawings for Murals, circa 1935 (Box OV 23)
    (Scanned with Box 18, F13)
- Scrapbooks, 1895-1963; Series 9; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 18-21, 25
  This series contains scrapbooks belonging to John and Marguerite Storrs. The earliest scrapbook, from Storrs' youth, contains newspaper and magazine clippings of articles and illustrations regarding military and political history. A scrapbook from the early 1900s also contains illustrations and advertisements from newspapers and magazines. A disbound scrapbook contains clippings about the dancer Maud Allan and other friends of Storrs as well as printed material from social events. Two additional scrapbooks contain news clippings and event announcements for the professional activities of both John and Marguerite Storrs. Also found in this series is a portfolio containing scattered items regarding the publication of Song of Myself with original wood engravings by John Storrs.
  One additional scrapbook was created by John Storrs around 1945 for his daughter, Monique Storrs, to document her service as a nurse in World War II. The scrapbook includes many photographs, military documents, correspondence, and other records. The back of the scrapbook contained many loose documents concerning the same subject.
  - Scrapbook, 1895-1898; (Oversized items housed in Box 20) (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Loose Items from Scrapbook, 1885-1898; (Oversized items housed in Box 20) (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Scrapbook (Disbound), circa 1901-1925; (Includes a photograph of John and Marguerite Storrs) (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook, circa early 1900s (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Portfolio for Song of Myself by Walt Whitman, 1921; (Oversized items housed in Box 20) (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1933-1939; (Includes a photograph of John and Maguerite Storrs) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1938-1952; (Oversized item housed in Box 21) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1945 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Loose Items from Scrapbook, 1957-1963; 1940-1945 (Box 25, Folder 37-38)
  - Oversize Scrapbook, 1895-1898 (Box 20)
    (Scanned with Box 18, F18)
  - Oversize Loose Items from Scrapbook, 1895-1898 (Box 20)
    (Scanned with Box 18, F19)
  - Oversize Portfolio for Song of Myself by Walt Whitman, 1921 (Box 20)
    (Scanned with Box 19, F2)
  - Oversize Scrapbook, 1938-1952 (Box 21)
    (Scanned with Box 19, F4)
- Estate Records, 1956-2002; Series 10; 0.4 Linear feet Box 26
  This series has not been digitized.
  This series contains records of John Storrs' estate immediately following his death in 1956, as well as records of several galleries that represented the estate in managing Storrs' artwork from the 1970s to 2002. Included are correspondence, contracts, legal records, financial records, price lists, sales records and other planning documents. Also found are a few records regarding the estate of Monique Storrs Booz.
  - General Estate Records, 2001; 1956-1991 (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
  - Robert Schoelkopf Gallery Ltd., 1969-1991 (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
  - Hirschl and Adler Galleries, Inc., 1991-1997 (Box 26, Folder 6-9)
  - Robert Henry Adams Fine Art, 1996-2002; 1992 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Estate of Monique Storrs Booz, 1986-1990 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Artwork Storage, 1991-1992 (Box 26, Folder 12)
- Video Recordings, circa 1980s; Series 11; 0.2 Linear feet Box 26-27
  This series contains three VHS videocassettes transferred from an unknown reel format containing footage, mostly personal in nature, that documents Storrs family life at Chantecaille and in Chicago, Illinois, in the 1930s. Of note is a recording of the Centry of Progress International Exposition.
  - "Chantecaille, Summer 1936", circa 1980s; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - "Chantecaille 1935", "Century of Progress 1933", and "Chicago 1931", circa 1980s; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - "Chantecaille/Family", circa 1980s; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 2)